Today is February 14th.
今天是2月14日
Valentine's Day!
也就是情人節！
I'm strangely excited about it.
我有一種奇特的興奮感
But if I let my guard down, I'll be teased by Takagi-san.
但要是我鬆懈的話 又會被高木同學捉弄了
I've got to stay calm.
我得維持平常心
I've got to stay calm!
平常心！
-Hey, Nishikata. -What?
-嘿，西片 -幹嘛？
It sure is cold today.
今天真的很冷
Sure is.
對啊
Everyone!
各位！
I made a ton of chocolate for Valentine's day.
我做了好多情人節巧克力
Help yourself if you'd like.
想吃的人可以來拿喔
-First come, first serve. -I'll take one.
-先來的人可以先拿喔 -我要一個
Me too.
我也要
-Thanks. -Here.
-謝謝 -給你
Thank you.
謝謝
-Thank you.
-謝謝
Here.
給你
-Here. -Thank you.
-給你 -謝謝
Aren't you going to get some?
你不去拿一些嗎？
No way I can go up there alone!
我總不能自己過去拿吧！
Totally.
對啦
But if this continues…
但要是再這樣下去…
It'll be zero chocolate for us again!
我們今年收到的 巧克力數量又會是零了！
You're right.
你說得沒錯
Hibino. Give me some too.
日日野，也給我一些吧
-You traitor! Wait up! -Thank you. Ouch!
-你這個叛徒，等等我！ -謝謝，好痛！
Hibino.
日日野
-Still some for me? -Of course.
-還有可以給我的嗎？ -當然
-Here you are. -Come on.
-給你 -我說你啊
Any chocolate will be confiscated.
帶巧克力來學校一律沒收
Didn't I tell you that, Hibino?
日日野，我沒告訴過你嗎？
Confiscated.
沒收
Forgive me!
老師，放過我吧！
Give it here.
交出來
-Okay. -Confiscated.
-好 -沒收
Sorry.
對不起
Confiscated!
沒收！
Teacher!
老師！
Please forgive us!
放過我們吧！
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Oh, nothing.
噢，沒什麼
Down to Yangzhou in the flowery mist of March…
煙花三月下揚州…
Stay calm.
平常心
Just stay calm.
我一定要維持平常心
…only to see it flowing into the horizon of the Yangtze River.
…唯見長江天際流
Hey, Nishikata.
嘿，西片
Yeah?
嗯？
Can I borrow your eraser?
我可以跟你借橡皮擦嗎？
Okay.
好
Thanks.
謝謝
Sure.
嗯
Damn it.
可惡
For a second I thought she might just casually give me chocolates.
有一秒鐘的時間 我以為她會若無其事地送我巧克力
But during class? Not a chance.
但在上課時根本就不可能
Hey, Nishikata.
嘿，西片
What?
幹嘛？
Yikes. That was close.
差一點，好險
I would have been told off again.
我差點又要被罵了
Damn it.
可惡
Can't get my hopes up. Don't expect anything.
不能太抱持希望，不能期待任何事
Mano, did you make that?
真野，那是你做的嗎？
Yeah. But I can't find the timing to give it to him.
對，但我找不到機會給他
I see.
這樣啊
But I'm sure Nakai is waiting for you.
但我想中井一定在等你
Looking for a chance to be alone with you.
想找機會和你獨處
Yeah. I hope so.
嗯，希望是這樣
-Did you get any chocolate? -I did!
-你有收到巧克力嗎？ -有！
I got some from Hibino. We almost got busted though.
我從日日野那裡拿到一些 但我們差點就被抓了
It almost got taken away by Mr. Tanabe.
巧克力差點就被田邊老師沒收了
He's terrifying when he's angry.
他生氣起來好可怕
You're so lucky, Nakai. She's here to give you chocolate.
真好啊，中井，她來這裡送你巧克力
I'm so jealous of you and Mano.
我真羨慕你和真野
You are?
是嗎？
Hey.
嘿
Nakai.
中井
What's up?
怎麼了？
Nothing.
沒什麼
Right when I finally get the courage to ask Hibino for chocolate…
我好不容易鼓起勇氣 向日日野要巧克力
…it gets confiscated.
然後就被沒收了
How about you?
你呢？
Did you get any?
你有收到嗎？
No, I only want it from one person anyway.
沒有，但我只希望收到某個人的
-Hojo? -Well, yeah.
-北條？ -嗯，對
What?!
什麼？
You? From Hojo?
你？和北條？
There's no way.
那是不可能的
Hamaguchi.
濱口
Be a man and face the facts.
你就當個男人，勇敢地放棄吧
Never.
不
I know she'll come through.
我知道她會來找我
And you? I'm sure you got some from Takagi-san, right?
你呢？你一定從高木同學那裡 收到巧克力了吧？
Well, I, um…
這個嘛，我，呃…
I don't want to hear it!
我不想聽！
Don't do this to us!
放過我們吧！
Come on.
過來啊
Go!
走！
-Hamaguchi. -Oh, Hojo. What is it?
-濱口 -噢，北條，怎麼了？
Do you want some chocolate?
你想要巧克力嗎？
Chocolate?
巧克力？
Oh, that's right. It's Valentine's Day.
噢，對喔，今天是情人節
I guess if you have some…
如果你要給我的話…
I see.
這樣啊
Here.
給你
Hurry up and take it.
快點收下啊
The teacher will see us.
不然會被老師看到
Thanks.
謝謝
You're welcome.
不客氣
See you.
再見
Lucky you, Hamaguchi.
太好了，濱口
Yeah.
嗯
Huh? What's wrong?
呃？怎麼了？
It's just…
只是…
This isn't handmade.
這不是手作的
What? Are you trying to start a fight?
什麼？你想打架嗎？
You're lucky to have gotten anything.
可以收到巧克力已經很幸福了
-It's Hojo! -That's not it.
-是北條耶！ -不是那個意思
I saw her at the supermarket yesterday.
昨天我在超市碰巧看到她了
What?
什麼？
I saw her buying ingredients to make homemade chocolate.
我看到她在買手作巧克力的材料
That means I'm not her crush.
所以說，她的本命巧克力 不是要送我的
Hamaguchi.
濱口
Hate to see it, Hamaguchi.
真可惜啊，濱口
Maybe she likes one of us instead.
也許她的本命巧克力 是要送給我們其中之一的
No way. I'm 100 percent sure.
怎麼可能？百分之百不可能
100 is too much. More like 90 percent?
百分之百太高了，百分之九十如何？
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
If I didn't get them, there's no way you will.
如果我沒收到，那你也不可能收到
What now?
現在是怎樣？
Hey.
嘿
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I promised Kimura and the guys I'd play soccer during the break.
我答應木村他們下課時一起踢足球
You did?
這樣啊？
That's fine. Go ahead.
那沒關係，你去吧
Okay then.
好喔
It's impossible.
什麼啊！
What's with you? You know I'm going to give you chocolate.
是怎樣？你知道我要送你巧克力吧
You big dummy!
你這個大笨蛋
Maybe he doesn't want my chocolate.
也許他不想收到我的巧克力
Mano.
真野
What do you want?
幹嘛？
Mano, are you angry or something?
真野，你是不是生氣了？
You blockhead.
呆瓜
"Blockhead"?
“呆瓜”？
Oh! Is this about Valentine's Day?
噢！該不會是情人節的事吧？
Would you like the chocolate I made?
你想要收到我做的巧克力嗎？
Do you want it?
你想要嗎？
Of course I do.
我當然想要
Okay then.
那麼
Here.
給你
Thank you.
謝謝
Sure.
嗯
You're going to eat it here?
你要在這裡吃啊？
Is that bad?
不行嗎？
This is great. What's in it?
這個好好吃啊，裡面加了什麼？
You dummy.
你這個笨蛋
I'm off to play soccer now.
那我去踢足球了
Dummy!
笨蛋！
-Nakai. -Yes?
-中井 -是
Nakai.
中井
Are you hiding something?
你是不是藏著什麼？
Pardon?
欸…什麼？
Oh, you mean this?
噢，這個啊？
It's the book I lent to Mano.
這是我借給真野的書
She just gave it back to me.
她剛才還給我
A book, huh?
書啊？
Small paperback perhaps?
小本平裝的書嗎？
Very well.
好喔
Good thing I ate it before it got confiscated.
我在它被沒收前就先吃了，不錯吧？
Dummy.
笨蛋
Forget soccer.
別踢足球了
Don't go.
別去了
-I'm going. -Why?
-我要去 -為什麼？
You are here
你在這裡
I am here
我在這裡
And when I turn around
而當我轉身
I see you smiling
我看見你微笑
The cherry blossoms bloom
櫻花盛開
The seasons changed…
季節變換…
Eyes on the mirror everyone. Open wide.
大家看著鏡子，嘴角上揚
…But you remained
…但你依然在那裡
Far, far in the distance
遙遠的地方
On the slope shimmering with heat
在冒著熱氣的坡道上
Even if the scenery were to change
就算風景改變
There are things that remain unchanged
也有不變的事物
Inside our hearts
長存在我們的心中
The happiness I receive
我因為遇見你
From meeting you
而得到的幸福
Let's walk together
讓我們並肩行走
And reflect upon it
然後回憶
In a year from now
在一年以後
In 10 years from now
在十年以後
Our memories remain the same
我們的回憶依舊
From now until forever
從現在直到永遠
The sky sure is pretty.
天空真美麗啊
-Hey, Hamaguchi. -Woah.
-嘿，濱口 -哇
Oh, Hojo.
噢，北條
You shouldn't walk with your head back and sigh with you're mouth open.
你真不應該一邊走路一邊仰頭嘆氣
It's scary, you look like a zombie.
真可怕，你看起來像僵屍一樣
Okay.
嗯
So, why were you so down in the dumps?
所以，你為什麼這麼沮喪？
I'm not.
我沒有啊
I'm fine.
我很好
Liar.
騙人
I heard you let out a big deep sigh.
我剛才聽見你大聲嘆了口氣
I know.
我知道了
You didn't receive enough chocolates.
一定是嫌你收到的巧克力不夠多吧
You're upset about the amount.
你對收到的數量不滿意
Boys are so childish.
男生都好幼稚喔
So?
所以呢？
How many did you get?
你收到幾個巧克力？
One.
一個
I guess.
的樣子
What?
什麼？
Only from me?
你只收到我的？
Yeah.
對
Well, you should be happy to get one from me.
好吧，那收到我的你應該感到高興
That's better than getting a bunch, right?
這比收到一大堆還好，對吧？
Yeah, it is.
是啊
-How about you? -Me?
-你呢？ -我？
How'd it go?
你怎麼樣？
How'd what go?
什麼怎麼樣？
Did you give the chocolates to your crush?
你把本命巧克力 送給你喜歡的人了嗎？
My crush?
本命巧克力？
You don't have to hide it.
你不用裝了
You made chocolates yesterday, right?
你昨天有做巧克力，對吧？
H-How do you know that?
你怎麼知道？
I happened to see you buying ingredients at the store.
我剛好看見你在店裡買材料
Those were…
那些…
I burnt them all.
全都燒壞了
I took my eyes off them for one second.
我一時不注意
Huh? Really?
欸？真的？
Besides, what do you mean by "crush"?
還有，你說 “本命巧克力”是什麼意思？
Chocolate is chocolate. It's just a gift. Nothing special.
巧克力就是巧克力 我全部都只送義理巧克力
Nothing to do with a "crush."
沒有本命巧克力
And also…
還有…
I only give them to those I want to.
我只送給了我想送的人
What?
什麼？
Does that mean…?
你的意思是說…
Only I got one?
你只有送給我？
Yeah, so what?
對，那又怎樣？
It's just…
就只是…
It's nothing.
沒什麼
Thank you.
謝謝
For the chocolate.
你的巧克力
You have to pay me back with something fancy on White Day.
白色情人節的時候 你要回贈我高級的東西
Sorry to keep you waiting!
抱歉讓你久等！
No way!
不會啦！
Nothing ended up happening.
結果什麼事也沒發生
But I didn't get teased on Valentine's Day so today's a big win.
但我在情人節當天沒被捉弄 所以今天算是大勝利
This has got to be chocolate--
這一定是巧克力…
-Nishikata! -Woah!
-西片！ -哇！
-What's that? -What's what?
-那是什麼？ -什麼是什麼？
Oh, this?
噢，這個？
It looks like some kind of box.
不知道耶，看起來像盒子
Oh?
噢？
It must be Kimura playing some kind of trick.
這一定是木村在玩什麼把戲
No, it isn't.
不是喔
How do you know?
你怎麼知道？
Because I know who put it there.
因為我知道是誰放的
You do?
你知道？
Yeah.
對
Who do you think it was?
你覺得是誰呢？
I think it's someone who's close to you right now.
我覺得是一個現在離你很近的人
It must be Takagi-san.
一定就是高木同學了
But how embarrassing if I'm wrong.
但要是猜錯了，也太丟臉了吧
But…
但是…
There's no one else it could be.
也沒有別人了
Do you have an idea, Nishikata?
西片，你有什麼想法嗎？
Any idea who it could be?
你覺得是誰呢？
I have no idea.
我完全不知道
And I don't want to know.
而且我也不想知道
Oh?
噢？
You know what day it is, don't you?
你知道今天是什麼日子吧？
Valentine's Day.
情人節
What's that?
你說什麼？
Bingo!
答對了！
Here's some chocolate.
我有帶巧克力
Huh?
嗯？
Here.
給你
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Don't want it?
你不想要？
It's not that.
也不是
Here.
給你
Thanks.
謝謝
As a friend.
這是義理巧克力
I know that.
我知道
The big box looks like it's for someone's crush.
那個盒子看起來是本命巧克力
What?
什麼？
Well…
嗯…
Who could it be from?
會是誰送的呢？
I don't know.
誰啊？
Nishikata.
西片
This one is just as friends.
這個是義理巧克力
Just that one…
只有那個…
"Just that one"?
“只有那個”？
Huh?
咦？
What?
什麼？
Come on, Nishikata. Let's go home.
走吧，西片，一起回家吧
Okay.
好
Yes?
請進
When you finish your homework, come downstairs, please.
等你寫完功課，請下樓一下
Okay. Will do.
好， 知道了
So…
那個…
We talked about this on New Year's Eve
我們在新年前夕那天有說過
about how we might have to move for your father's work.
我們可能要為了你爸爸的工作搬家
Well it's been officially decided.
現在已經正式決定了
At the end of March.
時間是三月底
I see.
這樣啊
I understand.
我知道了
Where will we move?
我們要搬去哪裡？
Paris.
巴黎
In France.
在法國
Paris?
巴黎？
Pretty far.
好遠啊
I'm sorry.
對不起啊
It's selfish of me.
爸爸很自私
No.
不會
It's not your fault.
這也沒辦法
It's your job.
畢竟是工作嘛